

#### Jem Walker

Translation & Interpretation

+1 (720) 548-0171

jem@jemwalker.co

1805 Prima Lane Evergreen, CO 80439 United States

# **Working Languages**

A English (UK and US varieties)

B French

C Spanish

### Skills

- Translation
- Interpretation (consec. and simul.)
- MT post-editing
- Proofreading
- Research source analysis
- · Desktop publishing
- Software
  - CAT tools (Trados, MemoQ, WordFast Pro)
  - o Microsoft Office suite
  - o Adobe Creative Cloud
  - Front-end web design (HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery)

#### **Awards**

 1<sup>st</sup> Prize, 15<sup>th</sup> United Nations St. Jerome Translation Contest (Student), 2020 Recent graduate in translation and interpretation from at the Middlebury Institute. Areas of specialization include wine, arts and culture, and information technology including cybersecurity. ATA and Colorado Translators' Association member; previous experience in politics and public administration. Passionate about bridging divides between people.

## **Experience**

#### **Freelance Translator and Interpreter**

**Based in Denver, Colorado** 

d.b.a. Jem Walker Translation & Interpretation

May 2021—

- Provide translation and interpretation services to a wide array of organizations across the world, including the Tokyo 2020+1 Olympics, the International Council of Museums and the Thales Group among others
- Continuing to focus on professional and skills development to bring bespoke, high-quality linguistic services to clients

#### **Asiatis Translation Agency**

Montréal, Québec

Intern

Jun—Sep 2020

 Translated and proofread various academic and technical texts as well as participating in video game localization projects

#### Office of the Governor of Colorado

Denver, Colorado

Intern

Sep—Nov 2018
vision by writing copy for

 Helped communicate the Governor's vision by writing copy for proclamations and correspondence with constituents

Administrative Assistant / Citizens' Advocate

Nov 2018—Jan 2019

- Continued responsibilities and projects from internship
- Frontline role, engaging with constituents and providing operational support

#### Scheduling Assistant

Jan—Jun 2019

- Joined scheduling team in new administration
- Created processes to ensure optimal planning of the Governor's time
- Connected with stakeholders to keep the day-to-day business of government running smoothly

#### Académie de Clermont-Ferrand

Auvergne, France

English Assistant/Teacher

Oct 2016—Apr 2017

 Developed English-language conversation skills in students aged 11-21, responding dynamically to help each student progress

### **Education**

Middlebury Institute of International Studies

Monterey, California

MA Translation and Interpretation (FR-EN)

2019-2021

**University of Leeds** 

Leeds, England

BA French and Politics (2:1 classification)

2014—2018

**Korea University** 

Seoul, South Korea

Intl. Summer Campus (US Foreign Pol. & Korean) 2015

Thank you for your consideration